# Huanzhuo Wu

August-Bebel-Str. 17a / A113, 01219 Dresden, Germany

□ +49 1746023602 | wuhuanzhuo@gmail.com | Ahuanzhuo.github.io | Google Scholar



# Summary\_

I am Huanzhuo Wu, a Junior researcher at the Deutsche Telekom Chair of Communication Networks (ComNets) at Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden), Germany. My particular research interest is In-network Computing, Software Defined Networks (SDN), and Algorithm Optimization, with more than 20 peer-reviewed publications and several research projects. For more detailed and up-to-date information about my projects, publications, and activities, please kindly refer to my personal website at https://huanzhuo.github.io.

# Work Experience \_\_

## Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden)

Dresden, Germany

JUNIOR RESEARCHER

Feb. 2017 - Present

- Coordinating and managing research projects, in cooperations with Ericsson, Robert Bosch GmbH, Huawei Munich Research Center, TU Munich, RWTH Aachen, and other key partners.
- Conducting research on In-network Computing and Industrial 5G, with publications, talks, and demos on e.g., IEEE GlobCom, IEEE ICC, IEEE Internet of Things Journal, CES, and Hanover Messe.
- Applying for funding on research projects and research marketization, i.e., 800K € from the Federal Ministry of Economics and Technology Germany in 2022, 100k € from the Federal Ministry of Education and Research Germany in 2020.
- · Teaching and supervising students.

Audi China Beijing, China

NTERN Aug. 2016 - Nov. 2016

- Managing and supporting projects related to digitization (Audi Connect, App Center, and Cloud Project).
- Supporting enterprise-university cooperation.

BMW AG Dingolfing, Germany

• Quality management by supporting SAP solution in production plant.

- Optimizing and updating the quality management metamodel.
- Creating quality reports.

## Education

INTERN

## Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden)

Dresden, Germany

May. 2015 - Oct. 2015

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Feb. 2017 - Present

- Topic: In-network Audio Processing for Low-latency Industrial Applications.
- Grad Year: Expected mid-2022.

#### Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden)

Dresden, Germany

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTE SCIENCE

April. 2012 - Dec. 2016

- Master Thesis: Regenerating Codes.
- Thesis Grade: 1.3.

TUDIAS Dresden, Germany

GERMAN LANGUAGE COURSE

Aug. 2011 - March. 2012

### **Chang'an University**

· Final Grade: DSH 2.

Xi'an, China

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTE ENGINEERING

Sept. 2007 - July. 2011

- Bachelor Thesis: Wireless Sensor Network.
- Final Grade: A.